### Contact

robiulhassan@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/rhsn1 (LinkedIn) mrh-jishan.github.io/mrh-jishan/ (Portfolio) github.com/mrh-jishan/ (Other)

### Top Skills

angular 4 Node.js Ruby on Rails

### Languages

English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

The Complete Angular Course: Beginner to Advanced

Ultimate AWS Certified Developer Associate 2020

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer 2020

NgRx (with NgRx Data) - The Complete Guide

Java Multithreading

#### Honors-Awards

BSC (HONS) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Querterly Star Award (Q3)

# Robiul Hassan

Full Stack Engineer | Spring-Boot | Angular | ReactJS | NodeJS | AWS

Singapore

# Summary

language independent ,results-oriented, and resourceful software engineer professional specialising in large scale software design and development. I believe that a new language or framework is just another tool and I would like to work with any technology which suits to the project.

On given any languages or frameworks, the project goal is achievable, only factor is time, money and resources and if anything that can be Written in JavaScript, will Eventually be Written in JavaScript...

I do have around 3+ years of experience in implementing and providing support for new software solutions, and development as well as demonstrated experience in micro-services architecture and implementing CI/CD pipelines using AWS.

Below are the teach skills I have been using in my previous projects so far:

- Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, Typescript, Ruby
- Frameworks: Spring-Boot, Angular, ReactJS, NodeJS, Ruby on Rails
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Postgres, DB2, Oracle, Redis
- DevOps & CI/CD: AWS, Docker, Jenkins, k8s, Maven, Git
- Testing Tools: Mockito, Rspec, jUnit, Jasmine, Mocha, Chai
- OS: Windows, Ubuntu, Arch Linux (Unix and Linux based preferred)
- IDE: Eclipse, VSCode, WebStorm, RubyMine
- Others: Socket, Pusher ,Kafka, ActiveMQ, Micro-Service, Shell Scripting

Note: Not attending any leetCode or Codility test by choice

Portfolio: https://mrh-jishan.github.io/mrh-jishan/

Medium: https://robiul-hassan.medium.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/mrh-jishan/

## Experience

### Cognizant

Project Associate | Full-stack Engineer October 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months) Singapore

- Develop corporate action services for clients to consume T24 OFS enquiry as well as GraphQL services
- Configure CI/CD pipeline setup on teamcity jobs and use ansible for server configuration.
- Worked on activeMQ, FTPS, and kafka for high frequency data transformation.
- Build DSL engine for clients to migrate DB2 data which reduced 30% load on the existing COBOL server.

#### Finterra

Frontend Developer

September 2017 - September 2019 (2 years 1 month)

Kuala Lumpur, Federal Territory of Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Worked on multiple projects to meet the deliverables with zero defect to the production.
- Redesign crowdfunding portal to decrease the run time by 50% by implementing lazy loading on Angular to gain more customers.
- Design the micro-service architecture and automate the CI/CD pipeline using AWS tools like S3, EKS, CodePipeline, and Docker.

#### Astro

Intern | Software Engineer

August 2017 - October 2017 (3 months)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Learn Salesforce visual-force and implemented new features for the sales team to increase the productivity.
- Redesign in-house WinLead portal to compatible with mobile screen and different browsers.

- Implemented Zip code validation for the sales zone on the sales portal.

# Education

Asia Pacific University of Technology and Innovation (APU / APIIT)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2015 - 2018)